<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Learn about Hugo Apéro on Hugo Apéro</title>
    <link>https://hugo-apero.github.io/apero/learn/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Learn about Hugo Apéro on Hugo Apéro</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://hugo-apero.github.io/apero/learn/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Customize your about page</title>
      <link>https://hugo-apero.github.io/apero/learn/about-page/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hugo-apero.github.io/apero/learn/about-page/</guid>
      <description>There are three main sections to the about page.
The header is on top, and includes a headline and subheadline. This section is optional.
The sidebar, which can appear on either the left or the right, is a narrow column with the option to include an avatar, audio file, social icons, and a quick list of links.
The main section is the wide column that appears next to the sidebar. It allows you to add an intro and outro, with featured content sandwiched between.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Customize your homepage</title>
      <link>https://hugo-apero.github.io/apero/learn/homepage/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hugo-apero.github.io/apero/learn/homepage/</guid>
      <description>Start customizing your Hugo Apéro homepage by opening up content/_index.md. When you open this file, you&amp;rsquo;ll see a long-ish section of YAML with a series of key-value pairs fenced in by three dashes (---). There is no content on this page below the YAML.
The underscore in the filename is important, and so is the filename, so don&amp;rsquo;t change this! But do focus on changing the YAML values.
Add an image     Place the homepage image in the static/ folder in the root of your website project (don&amp;rsquo;t add it to your themes/hugo-apero/static folder!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Set up your social</title>
      <link>https://hugo-apero.github.io/apero/learn/social/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hugo-apero.github.io/apero/learn/social/</guid>
      <description>There are five places where you can choose to show social icons. Here is the tl;dr:
 site header (set in config.toml), site footer (set in config.toml),  homepage (set in content/_index.md),  about page in the sidebar (set in content/about/sidebar/index.md), and  contact page (set in content/form/contact.md).  Read on to learn how to set up your social icons, and how to show/hide them.
Configure social     Wherever you end up wanting to show your social icons, you&amp;rsquo;ll need to start by setting up the links in your site config.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Style your site colors</title>
      <link>https://hugo-apero.github.io/apero/learn/color-themes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hugo-apero.github.io/apero/learn/color-themes/</guid>
      <description>You can totally customize your site&amp;rsquo;s theme colors within minutes of creating a new site. Read on to find out how, and decide which of the three options meets your needs.
Use a color theme     Hugo Apéro includes 8 built-in color themes that work &amp;ldquo;out of the box.&amp;rdquo; This means you can use a color theme to quickly customize the look of your site without needing to write any CSS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Style your site typography</title>
      <link>https://hugo-apero.github.io/apero/learn/fonts/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hugo-apero.github.io/apero/learn/fonts/</guid>
      <description>As with color themes, you can completely customize your site&amp;rsquo;s fonts within minutes of creating a new site. How you do it depends on how much control and customization you need.
Embedded fonts     Hugo Apéro includes 6 embedded fonts that work &amp;ldquo;out of the box.&amp;rdquo; We selected 3 serif and 3 sans-serif options that we thought looked good with this theme, in our humble opinions. All embedded fonts include real italics so you may emphasize to your heart&amp;rsquo;s content ❤️!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using panelsets</title>
      <link>https://hugo-apero.github.io/apero/learn/seedling/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hugo-apero.github.io/apero/learn/seedling/</guid>
      <description>Courtesy of panelset.js by Garrick Aden-Buie, from his xaringanExtra package: https://pkg.garrickadenbuie.com/xaringanExtra/#/panelset
For example, this panelset:
Hello! 👋 hello
 Goodbye 💨 goodbye
  Was created by combining this theme&amp;rsquo;s panelset and panel shortcodes:
{{&amp;lt; panelset class=&amp;#34;greetings&amp;#34; &amp;gt;}} {{&amp;lt; panel name=&amp;#34;Hello! :wave:&amp;#34; &amp;gt;}} hello {{&amp;lt; /panel &amp;gt;}} {{&amp;lt; panel name=&amp;#34;Goodbye :dash:&amp;#34; &amp;gt;}} goodbye {{&amp;lt; /panel &amp;gt;}} {{&amp;lt; /panelset &amp;gt;}} You could also revert to HTML as well. For example, this panelset:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CSS Grid Scaffold</title>
      <link>https://hugo-apero.github.io/apero/learn/css-grid-scaffold/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hugo-apero.github.io/apero/learn/css-grid-scaffold/</guid>
      <description>“Grid is the very first CSS module created specifically to solve the layout problems we&amp;rsquo;ve all been hacking our way around for as long as we&amp;rsquo;ve been making websites.”     — Chris House, A Complete Guide to CSS Grid Layout 1
 Overview     Since I began building websites in Y2K, I&amp;rsquo;ve lost count how many times the phrase &amp;ldquo;&amp;hellip;there&amp;rsquo;s got to be a better way to do this&amp;rdquo; has passed my lips.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Built-in Contact Form</title>
      <link>https://hugo-apero.github.io/apero/learn/built-in-contact-form/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hugo-apero.github.io/apero/learn/built-in-contact-form/</guid>
      <description>Formspree makes it easy to receive submissions from HTML forms on your static website.      Functional Form     This theme has a form-to-email feature built in, thanks to the simple Formspree integration. All you need to activate the form is a valid recipient email address saved in the front matter of the form (/content/forms/contact.md). Of course, the example shown below (your@email.here) must not be used.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
